http://www.rscds.org/legals-privacy-cookies

Privacy policy
The Royal Scottish Country Dance Society (RSCDS) is committed to protecting the security of your personal information in accordance with the principles set out in the Data Protection Acts (DPA) of 1994 and 1998 and the General Data Protection Regulations 2018. This policy explains how we use the personal information that you provide to us.
What information do we collect?
We collect information about you when you become a member with us. This allows RSCDS to administer your membership and provide you with agreed member benefits by email or post. In this case, we will collect your name, address and email address.
We will also collect information when you register with us, place an order for our products or services, sign up for an event or register for exams. In these cases we will only collect the information necessary to allow us to process your order, administer your booking or manage your attendance at an exam. This will include your contact details, including your name and address, your telephone number and, if necessary, your job title. We do not store financial information, such as bank account or credit card numbers.
We may also hold information when you complete a survey or send us an enquiry.
We also collect information about your use of our websites and how you arrived at our website in the first place. This can include what links or adverts of ours you have viewed or clicked on to reach us, or any search terms you have used. We can also see which pages of our websites have been viewed by you and for how long. All this information helps tell us what content is popular with our customers so we can improve our services and products.
How will we use this information about you?
RSCDS has a lawful basis under the General Data Protection Regulations when we process information in order to administer your membership, event booking or exam, or when we do so to process a shop order. This is because the processing is necessary in order to provide you with a service, process your order, manage your account or ensure quality monitoring. This information will only be used for those purposes.
RSCDS may seek your consent if we wish to process information for any other purpose. We will only process your information in such a manner if we receive your proactive consent to do so. We may seek such consent when we wish to distribute marketing information, undertake market research or share other content, which is appropriate for our audience.
Will we pass this information on to other companies?
We process RSCDS member information on our website, which can be accessed securely by appointed officials within that member’s Branch. This processing will only take place to allow us and the Branch to manage or administer your membership. In this case, both parties have a lawful basis for processing the information, as long as it is used for no other purpose.
We may also share information with Teachers, event venues or event staff, where necessary, for managing your attendance at an event or an exam. This information will be used only for these purposes, and for no other.
Information will not be shared with any other third parties for any other purpose, except where we have a lawful basis for doing so in order to fulfil a legal, contractual or safeguarding commitment.
How do we keep your information secure?
We take the security of your information very seriously and are certified to ISO 27001 standard. We use multiple layers of firewalls to ensure user data is kept as secure as possible, specialist devices to detect and prevent intrusion attempts, and encryption systems to ensure data is scrambled while being transmitted from system to system. We employ equally rigorous physical security policies to prevent physical access to our data centres. We perform regular system patching and employ an independent security company to perform penetration tests (authorised attempts to try to hack our systems to show any risks) annually and when we bring new systems online. We ensure that third parties employ the same rigour when handling data, ensuring that they apply security far in excess of regulatory requirements.
How long will we keep information?
We will only keep information about you for as long as we need to fulfil our obligations to you. We make sure that any third parties who may process your information on our behalf do the same. We have an internal retention policy with varying retention periods for different categories of information depending on our legal obligations and whether there is a commercial need to retain the information, such as to help us answer member account queries. After a retention period has elapsed, the data is deleted.
Other websites
Our websites may contain links to the websites of other organisations. This privacy policy only applies to our websites so, when you link to other websites, you should read their own privacy policies and terms and conditions. We cannot accept responsibility for your use of these websites.
Credit card policy
All transactions made on the RSCDS website are safe and secure. To comply with the current legislation we would like to remind everyone that the RSCDS no longer accepts credit card numbers via email or post and we do not hold any credit card information on-site.
The RSCDS accepts payment by cash in person, by credit card over the phone or by cheque.
Thank you for your understanding and for further information please get in touch with our Finance Officer Sandra Parish at: sandra.parish@rscds.org.
How we use cookies
Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers that we transfer to your computer’s hard drive through your web browser to enable our systems to recognise your browser and to provide personalised information.
The Help menu on most browsers will tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies altogether. Additionally, you can disable or delete similar data used by browser add-ons. However, because cookies allow you to take advantage of some of our websites’ features, we recommend that you leave them turned on.
If you do leave cookies turned on, be sure to sign out of any logged-in service when you finish using a shared computer.
Changes to our privacy policy
We keep our privacy policy under regular review and we will place any updates on this webpage. If there is a material change that could have an effect on you, we will notify you by placing a prominent announcement on our web pages.
Your rights
You have the right to ask for a copy of the information held by us in our records, in return for which we will charge a small fee. You also have the right to require us to correct any inaccuracies in your information. We respect your right to privacy. If you tell us that you do not wish to have your information used in the ways we have specified, we will respect your wishes. If you would like a copy of some or all of the personal information we hold about you, please write to us:
Your rights change from 25th May 2018. From this date, all individuals who provide us with personal information have the right to:
Be informed;
Access their information;
Request erasure;
Request rectification;
Request that processing is restricted;
Object to the use of their information;
Data portability;
For more information about these rights, and what they mean for you, please visit: https://ico.org.uk/for-the-public/
If you would like to make an access request using these rights, you can do so by contacting us:
RSCDS, 12 Coates Crescent, Edinburgh, Scotland EH3 7AF
The Royal Scottish Country Dance Society (RSCDS) is registered as a Scottish Charitable Company Limited by Guarantee, Charity No. SC 016085 / Company No. SC 480530
Sign up for the RSCDS eNewsletter
Sign up to:
Keep up to date with RSCDS events
Join a worldwide community of Scottish country dance and music
First name
Second name
Your email address
Yes, I would like to receive the regular RSCDS newsletter.
Join an RSCDS Branch & receive member benefits
There are 159 RSCDS Branches and over 300 Affiliated Groups in more than 50 countries around the world, located on all continents (except Antarctica).
They organise and run classes, dances and other social events in their own areas and are committed to helping develop Scottish Dance and Music for future generations.
We encourage you to try Scottish Country Dancing for yourself to see just how much fun it can be, so please come along and learn how to 'Dance Scottish'.
Wherever you are in the world there is most likely Scottish Country Dancing.
New to Scottish Country Dancing?
Jean Milligan Memorial Fund (JMMF)
What is Scottish Country Dance & music?
What is Step Dancing?
What is Highland Dancing?
What is Ceilidh Dancing?
New to Scottish Country Dancing?
Where to Ceilidh dance?
What is Scottish Country Dance & music?
What is Step Dancing?
What is Highland Dancing?
Core Training for Instructors (CTI)
